Mohammed Mubarek

050-284-981 0559-237-053

skinyynigg334@gmail.com • <u>linkedin.com/in/mubarak-mohammed-a9b82b2a1</u> GW-0062-3215

A 125 Opah Road, Accra, Ghana

OBJECTIVE

Final year Computer science student with strong aptitude for programming, math and logic. A natural born leader, yet a good team player with multitasking skills. Practical experience in Software engineering and Machine learning, with also an interest in research.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Computer science (First class)

Expected -September 2024

Accra Institute of Technology • Accra, Ghana (Kwame Nkrumah University of science and technology • Kumasi, Ghana) - Affiliated

• Undergraduate thesis on the topic "Detection and Analysis of Brain Tumor from MRI images using Transfer Learning with Resnet": Applied Deep learning in Medical Healthcare.

SKILLS

- Java
- C++
- PHP and Laravel (Backend web development)
- Dart and Flutter (Mobile App development)
- Python (Machine learning and deep learning)
- HTML AND CSS
- MATLAB
- · Git and GitHub
- Databases (MYSQL, POSTGRESS, MONGODB)
- · Java Spring Boot -Beginner

WORK EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

SEPT 2023 – Present

Accra institute of technology • Accra, Ghana

- Tutored first and second year students in Engineering Mathematics I (Algebra and Calculus I),
 Engineering Mathematics II (Calculus II and Differential Equations), and Engineering Statistics.
- Assisted Lecturers with supervision and invigilation of Quizzes, Assignments and examinations.

Amalitech Ghana (Service Center) East Legon • Accra, Ghana

- Wrote part of the Tourist Guide Mobile project as a Flutter developer on the tourist guide mobile team
- Gained Mentorship from Team mentor and team members in Mobile development with flutter, and equipped myself with the habit of writing clean code.
- · Contributed in team meetings, and Sprint plannings
- · Gained Mentorship from my work mentor in Backend Development with Laravel and Node JS.
- Gained proficiency in using version control tools (Git and GitHub).
- Learned best software development practices and gained a thorough industry experience.

VOLUNTEER WORK

Junior PHP developer

April 2023 - May 2023

Learning & Instructional Technologies Innovation Systems (LITIS dept) • Accra Institute of Technology, Accra Ghana

 Gained industry experience and mentorship from Experienced engineers in software development

Research Assistant

Feb 2024 - Present

Department of Computer science • Accra Institute of Technology, Accra Ghana

 Gained research experience by working under a faculty member in research in the field of Human Computer Interaction and Persuasive Software systems.

Member of the Student's Academic committee

Feb 2023 - Present

Students Representative Council (SRC) • Accra Institute of Technology, Accra Ghana

Assisted and Mentored Junior colleagues with all Academic related dilemmas

AWARDS AND HONOURS